Rashad Ali, Software Developer

Chicago, United States, rashadnm01@gmail.com

PROFILE

Highly driven and accomplished 21-year-old software developer with an impressive background in leading roles for successful startup companies. With 4+ years of professional experience and 8+ years of freelancing expertise, I have played a key role in securing over \$1M in startup funding for various ventures.

Notable Milestones:

- Completed CodeAbode Chicago's Web & Android App Bootcamp in 2015.
- Accepted into Milwaukee School of Engineering at the young age of 16 in 2018.
- Started contracting for NADAVerse before dropping out of college in 2020.
- Attended General Assembly's Software Engineering Immersive in September 2021.
- Initiated my career as a full stack developer at RadPoker in December 2021, contributing to front-end
 enhancements and back-end development using React TypeScript and Scala/NodeJs.
- Founded Ali Tech Solutions in July 2022, overseeing a team of 4-7 software developers, training entry-level developers, and managing the development of the company website.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Feb 2023 — Present

Lead Software Developer, Wall Street Blast

Remote

- Spearheaded the development of the Minimum Viable Product (MVP) and successfully secured over \$500k+ in startup funding.
- Managed and mentored a team of 2-3 entry-level developers as a leader within my freelance company.
- Proficiently utilized cutting-edge technologies including React, Node.js, Express, WebSockets, Heroku, and PostgresQL to server application.

Dec 2021 — Jul 2023

Lead Frontend Developer, RadPoker

Milwaukee

- Utilized React TypeScript to maintain and enhance the front-end of the application, overseeing code reviews and making customizations to elements such as the poker game board, game controls, modals, leaderboards, and more.
- Developed a unique betting control in React TypeScript, enabling players to raise their bid amount by horizontally dragging their finger, enhancing user interaction and engagement.
- Leveraged both Scala and NodeJs to create efficient backend functions responsible for filtering user data
 and retrieving contest information, crucial for displaying dynamic content on the frontend.

Sep 2020 — Jan 2022

Software Engineer, NADAVerse

Remote

- Designed and developed a dynamic timeline using React to visually showcase the progression of the NADAVerse, providing users with an engaging and informative experience.
- Took charge of deploying website updates to GoDaddy using cPanel, ensuring smooth and seamless
 integration of changes to the live environment, minimizing downtime, and maintaining optimal website
 performance.

EDUCATION

May 2015 — Sep 2023

Certificate, CodeAbode Chicago

Chicago

• Bootcamp focused on the development of web & android applications.

Sep 2021 — Dec 2021

Certificate, General Assembly

Remote

General Assembly's Software Engineering Immersive

SKILLS	JavaScript	Expert	Java	Experienced
	React	Expert	Scala	Skillful
	HTML5	Expert	WebSockets	Expert
	CSS	Expert	SQL	Experienced
	Node.js	Expert	Wordpress	Experienced
	Express	Expert	Shopify	Experienced

Python Skillful MongoDB Expert